KHUSHKARAN SINGH BAJWA

07595877695 https://github.com/khushkaran http://www.khushkaran.com

SUMMARY

At 14 I began developing in HTML/CSS, moving onto Adobe Flash, dabbling in Alias Maya, Sony Vegas and Final Cut. Then began developing and deploying iOS Apps, some of which are still for sale on the App Store. I then joined Makers Academy in February 2014 to hone my programming skills.

Specialties: HTML, CSS, Ruby, Javascript, Bootstrap, Rails, jQuery, AJAX, Testing (RSpec, Capybara, Sinon, Chai, Mocha), Git, Deployment (Heroku/Digital Ocean), iOS Development.

EXPERIENCE

CAUSEWAY TECHNOLOGIES

08 / 2014 - Present

Software Engineer

· Developing web applications for an developmental platform using various frameworks such as Rails, Sinatra & Node.js • Using languages such as Ruby, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, libraries such as jQuery, Bootstrap, SASS, LESS to extend features, and template engines such as ERB. • Ensuring quality code by testing functionality using unit tests (RSpec, Sinon, Mocha, Chai) and acceptance tests (Capybara) • Working in an Agile environment in a Scrum team to develop quality code that is maintainable and extendable, following the Software Craftsmanship Manifesto.

KESRI NISHAAN 09 / 2012 - Present

Web Developer

Developer working on flagship software in the Kesri Nishaan product range. Using both iOS and web technologies to ensure a rich experience for all users.

ADAPTIVE WEB LTD 07 / 2014 - 08 / 2014

Web Developer

· Using PHP to develop immersive and responsive web applications for various clients · Placing projects under Git Version Control in order to remain organised • Working in a team to provide results during tight deadlines

MAKERS ACADEMY 02 / 2014 - 05 / 2014

Developer

MENZIES AVIATION 01 / 2013 - 02 / 2014

Aircraft Dispatcher

· Coordinating various parties to ensure a safe and secure on-time departure · Calculating weight and balance of aircraft in a timed and highly-pressurised environment • Re-organised stakeholder reporting methods, increased accuracy and efficiency • Trained colleagues on using newly implemented methods and various other aspects • Rearranging passengers' flights after cancellations and missed departures • Providing passengers with an organised and professional presence on arrival to stand

03/2011 - 09/2012 **BMIBABY**

Aircraft Dispatcher

· Coordinating various parties to ensure a safe and secure on-time departure · Calculating weight and balance of aircraft in a timed and highly-pressurised environment

EDUCATION

2014 - 2014
2008 - 2011
2005 - 2007
2000 - 2005

INTERESTS

Classical Indian Music, Travelling, Sikh martial arts, Non-profit management, media production, developing mobile applications

LANGUAGES

- English (Native or bilingual proficiency)
- Panjabi (Native or bilingual proficiency)
- Hindi (Limited working proficiency)
- Urdu (Limited working proficiency)
- French (Elementary proficiency)

Year Council, School Council